SANJEEWA RANULUGE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT



+642040698789



sbandara725@gmail.com



www.sranulugedev.info



<u>LinkedIn</u>



<u>GitHub</u>



15A, Kenilworth Street, Addington, Christchurch, New Zealand

SKILLS

- JavaScript, Typescript, PHP, Python
- · Linux, Oracle VM VirtualBox, Docker, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Github Actions
- ReactJs, NextJs, NodeJs. Redux Express.Js, Redux, Toolkit, Redux-Thunk, Redux-Saga, Axios, GraphQL, REST Formik, Material UI, APIs, styled-components, TailwindCss
- React Native
- Unit Testing JEST
- MySQL, MongoDB
- · GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket, JIRA
- · Problem solving and analytical skills
- · Ability to work effectively in cross function teams
- Continuous Learning

OBJECTIVE

With 3+ years experience as a skilled and dedicated Software Engineer specializing in JavaScript | PHP | Python, my objective is to utilize my expertise to create dynamic and responsive web applications that push the boundaries of user interactivity and enhance overall user experiences. With a solid foundation in JavaScript frameworks and libraries, including React and Node.js, I am committed to developing efficient and maintainable code that meets the highest quality standards.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

February -2023 - To date

- Freelancing
- Actively engage in online courses and personal projects to enhance technical and professional skills and improve problem-solving abilities.

Software Engineer

Aeturnum Lanka (Pvt)

October 2021 - January 2023

Project Domain: Health Care

Complete revamping for a legacy Electronic Medical Records EMR solution. The platform is designed for clinicians to prioritize the clinical experience. The result is a comprehensive suite that works with clinicians to deliver better care and compliance.

Front end development using Ant Design, ReactJS, Git, Bitbucket, Jira, REST, JEST(unit test)

Responsibilities

- Developed several user interfaces and methods for functional requirements based on figma designs.
- · Researched and found solutions for technical issues
- Implemented the identified solution by coordinating the team.
- Covered the unit testing and application end-to-end testing.
- · Interacted with clients to gather requirements, and provided regular project updates
- Provided technical guide to junior developers throughout the development phase

Project Domain: E-Commerce Platform

Front end development using NextJS, Redux Toolkit, Material UI, Formik, Git, GitHub, Jira, REST, Axios

Responsibilities

- Developed several user interfaces and methods for functional requirements and API binding based on figma designs.
- Code review
- Implemented the identified solution by coordinating the team.
- Maintained and improved the existing code bases and peer-reviewed code changes.
- Provided technical guide to junior developers throughout the development phase.
- · Delivered presentations to stakeholders, effectively communicating progress, and technical details to diverse audiences.

EDUCATION

BSc. Industrial Statistics and Mathematical Finance

University of Colombo Sri Lanka

2014 Dec -2017 Dec

Hands on knowledge in Computer Science, Game Theory, Actuarial Mathematics, Statistics, Operations Research and Financial Mathematics

REFEREES

Referees will be provided upon request.

Software Engineer

TechLead International (Pvt) Ltd January 2021 – September 2021

Project Domain: E-learning platform

An e-learning platform to connect students and teachers

Backend development using PHP, Mysql and Front end development using Html and CSS and

Responsibilities

- Modified applications to resolved bugs, upgrade interfaces and improve performance.
- · Researched and found solutions for technical issues
- Implemented the identified solution by coordinating the team.
- Design the software architecture and interfaces for the component to meet functional and performances requirements.
- Developed Mass communication method (connecting teachers and students) using a SMS gateway.
- Provided technical guide to junior developers throughout the development phase

Associate Software Engineer

TechLead International (Pvt) Ltd December 2019 – January 2021

Project Domain: E-Commerce Platform

Front end development using Next.JS, Typescript, Rest API binding using GraphQL and Apollo Client

Responsibilities

- Successfully implemented the several features with REST API binding for web site (Shopping Cart feature and Authentication process)
- Developed User interfaces for the component to meet functional and performances requirements..
- Handled payment gateway for payment method

Online food delivery mobile application

Front end development using React Native, Redux, Redux Saga, axios Responsibilities

- Successfully implemented the several features with REST api binding for Mobile app
- Developed User interfaces for the component to meet functional and performances requirements..

Internship

TechLead International (Pvt) Ltd June 2019 – December 2019

Mobile App(e-commerce) - React Native

Responsibilities

 Developed several user interfaces and methods for functional requirements and API binding using Axios

Telicom multimeter projec

Frontend development using PHP and Laravel-PHP framework, mysql

Brandix Apparel Solutions Limited Feb 2018 – Aug 2018

Responsibilities

- Time and action planning
- Coordinating frontend and plant through pre production meetings